Guide to the Ross Rieder Audio and Video Collection
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Ross Rieder Audio and Video Collection
1981-2014
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5930
5930-001
Rieder, Ross K.
.54 cubic feet 2 boxes
Ross Rieder served as president of the Pacific Northwest Labor History Association for 37 years from 1978 to 2015. This collection contains audio and video recordings of labor-related programs as collected by Ross Rieder.
Ross Rieder is a union activist, labor historian, and preservationist. Rieder served as president of the Pacific Northwest Labor History Association for 37 years from 1978 to 2015, and remains a member and active supporter of the PNLHA. Before retiring, Rieder was a music teacher and a member of the Everett American Federation of Teachers local union. Rieder also worked for the the Snohomish County Central Labor Council and Washington State Federation of Labor. Other achievements by Rieder during his career in labor include his co-leadership (with Will Parry) of a Washington State Labor Council campaign in 1978-1979 to assist King County unions to organize workers in picketing automobile dealerships in reaction to a growing trend among the dealerships to open their shops to non-union work.
Parry and Ross paired again to organize the Washington State delegation of union members and supporters for Solidarity Day -- a rally against the Reagan administration initiated by the AFL-CIO Executive Council and held in Washington, D.C., on September 19, 1981. Later, Rieder co-hosted a labor radio show on KSER (Everett) called "Part of the Union" between and served as president of the AFT retiree chapter in Washington.
Contains Ross Rieder's collection of labor-related audio and video recordings including audio recordings of his radio show "Part of the Union" (2005-2012) and DVD recordings of the monthy television production, "Our View", as broadcast on community cable channels across the state (2006-2014).
Some restrictions on access. Contact repository for details.
Ross Rieder, null
Pacific Northwest Labor History Association (Mss Coll 4552-002)
PNLHA related materials were relocated to the Pacific Northwest Labor History Association records (4552-002), 2016-03-16.
Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records;;; Labor History; Labor Unions; Sound Recordings; Moving Images
- Experiments in Democracy: Worker's Co-ops (produced by Doug Honig, KRAB), 1981 (Box 1)
- Race, Work, and Economic Justic Conference recordings, April 3-4, 1998 (Box 1)
- BC Tech Conference recordings, March 12-15, 1986 (Box 1)
- PNW Labor Conference, no date (Box 1)
- The Triangle Fire as Told by Leon Stein, 1986 (Box 1)
- ET and the Boy at Folklife, May 23-24, 2009 (Box 1)
- SPEEA Strike Documentary, no date (Box 1)
- KPFA Labor Collective May Day/Western Workers Labor Heritage Festival, 2004 (Box 1)
- Definitions of Democracy by Dan Leahy, no date (Box 1)
- Labor History Images Prepared by SPEEA for Ross Rieder Labor History Lecture, June 2010 (Box 1)
- NSW Mines Rescue Pty Ltd Training and Introduction to the Virtual Reality Facilities, no date (Box 1)
- AWPPW The Story of a Democratic Union (Box 1)
- Voices of Labor recordings, no date (Box 1)
- Our View DVD recordings, October 2006-December 2014 (Box 1)
- Part of The Union audio recordings (incomplete run), June 2005-October 2012 (Box 2)